Finding Aid for Filipino-American Presbyterian Church, Southfield, Mich., records, 2000-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Filipino-American Presbyterian Church, Southfield, Mich., records 2000-20005
Filipino-American Presbyterian Church (Southfield, Mich.)
0.5 linear feet
06118 Ba 2
The Filipino-American Presbyterian Church was established in 2000. The records contain correspondence, meeting minutes, agendas, church publications and reports.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group came from Jean Loup (donor no. 8656 ) on September 19, 2006.
The collection is open to research.
The Filipino-American Presbyterian Church, New Church Development (NCD) was established in 1999. Previous to its establishment, the church started off with a few families who worshipped from house to house. As the congregation grew, worship was then held at Greenfield Presbyterian Church, Berkley, MI. Reverend Fred Baliad presided over worship. The church moved to a permanent location at the Southfield Presbyterian Church under Rev. Fe Esperanza B. Ayap. The congregation organized and participated in various activities such as community fundraisers, cultural events, charities, hosting of special guests, national conferences, and assisting new Filipino immigrants.
The Filipino-American Presbyterian Church records are organized into two series: Church History and Administrative Activities. Together, these series contain meeting minutes, agendas, photographs, reports, publications, and correspondence.
Subjects:
Filipino-American Presbyterian Church (Southfield, Mich.); Filipino Americans--Michigan.; Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)--Michigan--Southfield.; Southfield (Mich.)--Church history.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Church History
  - Background, 2000-2003 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000-2005 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Programs, 2000-2005 (Box 1)
  - Publications
    - Flyers (Box 1)
    - Newsletters, 2000-2004 (Box 1)
    - New Church Development (NCD) anniversary programs, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    - Sunday Worship programs, 2000-2005 (Box 1)
- Administrative Activities
  - Administrative Commission agendas and minutes, 2000-2005, 2 folders and 1 notebook (Box 1)
  - Church Pastor Employment, 2001-2005 (Box 1)
  - Music Education Director, 2002 (Box 1)
  - New Church Development (NCD) steering committee, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - Pastor's Reports, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
  - Synod Report, 2002-2003 (Box 1)